<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-01T22:51:27-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">american-epic</title><subtitle>Repository for Poem Chapters</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Chapter 5: Connecticut Border</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/30/chapter-5-connecticut-border.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 5: Connecticut Border" /><published>2025-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/30/chapter-5-connecticut-border</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/30/chapter-5-connecticut-border.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-5-connecticut-border">Chapter 5: Connecticut Border</h1>

<p>We rush along to the lot, more of a junkyard if we’re lacking tact<br />
With cars, robots, drones, cranes and all types of machinery disassembled<br />
The clock strikes noon, and over a loudspeaker we hear<br />
A shrill voice leading a demonic midday prayer</p>

<p>“Chosen ones, find it in your heart to stamp out hate at any cost<br />
Your life, their life, one in the same, is proper blood spilled<br />
Those fallen before you, were culled as they should be.”</p>

<p>A massive belltower dings twelve times, and my guide says to me,<br />
“That’s your cue my son to get out of this state.<br />
By nightfall the streets teem with infernal practicing<br />
Their extracurriculars in hopes of finding in-flesh hosts and moments of reckoning.”</p>

<p>I help him hoist a tarp revealing five obscure vehicles, all from different eras<br />
He winks, “just because I look Victorian does not mean,<br />
I have not learned to get my hands dirty.</p>

<p>Be swift, and take 90 to the west<br />
Your road gets brighter, I’m sure, when you hit Connecticut<br />
For me I’m back to the haunted train where we first met<br />
As something tells me there’s more travelers coming<br />
To witness the chaos of this century<br />
And perhaps, just perhaps, a way to steer clear of this agony.”</p>

<p>“My friend, before I go, I cannot thank you enough<br />
For shielding me from this ominousness, maybe even death<br />
There’s one question I ask before I’m on my way<br />
A man named La Croix
Is he alive in this century?</p>

<p>“A wise idea to investigate such a figure<br />
He indeed drops in from time to time.<br />
Head to New York-
You’d find him there, if he’s currently on our timeline.”</p>

<p>Slightly confused by his coyness, I don’t question it and try to head off<br />
As I eagerly choose the most obscure car on the lot<br />
But still I cannot go,<br />
Sitting completely flummoxed by a car with no pedal, brake, nor steering wheel.<br />
My guide laughs heartily, and presses the ignition</p>

<p>A robotic voice hums over the speaker:<br />
“Please choose your destination or your coordinates.”<br />
Not sure where I’m to go, I blurt out the first place in my mind,<br />
“Krispy Pizza, Brooklyn, NYC.”<br />
The machine pauses and responds monotone<br />
“I’m sorry your destination does not exist, but I found these coordinates,<br />
If they will suffice in its place.”</p>

<p>“Good as ever, now make haste,<br />
“Hurry! Please! This place gives me the creeps.”</p>

<p>I sit in awe as my vehicle whirrs away<br />
Calmy touching seventy on city streets<br />
With no cars in sight, I make it to the highway.</p>

<p>Avoiding pothole madness in a reverse game of whack-a-mole<br />
MassDOT obviously disappeared with the tightening of the purse<br />
But who could blame them with this thoroughfare so hauntingly empty.<br />
Eventually 90 became 84 and we headed southwest<br />
To a state border crossing, one I had yet to see, oh so ominous</p>

<p>Miles of abandoned vehicles and trailers, glowing with neon lights<br />
Gargoyles perched on every road-sign<br />
A fair warning to those not welcome, “you’d best turn around.”<br />
Still I pressed along confident in my intent<br />
When I come to a full stop flat<br />
An archway above so agonizingly close, preventing my crossing.</p>

<p>A border patrolman comes out, inching closer, a rifle abreast<br />
Surveying me and my vehicle, whether I’m any type of threat<br />
A bright light flashes from his pocket<br />
Too soon for me to blink<br />
He yells with assertion, “State your destination.”</p>

<p>My hands clam up, my brow lined with sweat<br />
“Oh dear god, what do I say?<br />
Its true I’m just passing through, but is that information sufficient?”</p>

<p>“New York City sir, to visit a cousin for a reunion”<br />
I hope my intuition works to keep it short and sweet.</p>

<p>The guard’s face grows stern as he approaches nearer<br />
“You’re not in the national database, now cut out the lies.<br />
And if you don’t, I’m trained to assume<br />
You’re a New Hampshire spy, and your crime at my border is treason.”</p>

<p>He demanded my wallet and started shuffling through it<br />
Anger turned to confusion as he started uncovering its contents<br />
White knuckling an expired stack of credit cards<br />
“What the point of counterfeiting artifacts so obtuse?”</p>

<p>Until the final card he unveils<br />
It immediately uplifts his tune<br />
A card, I sometimes forget,<br />
That has been in my possession for years<br />
It reveals an ode to a land of steep cliffs enveloped in fog<br />
With a blessing of hope, in deep times of need<br />
And in sudden revelation his world view makes sense<br />
His scowl morphs into a shape far less obscene</p>

<p>He steps back, his rifle withdrawn<br />
A moment of longing, etched on his face<br />
He closes his eyes, mutters something, deep in contemplation</p>

<p>“Its so rare these days to see relics of faith in these northern parts<br />
And coupled with these plastic relics,<br />
Who am I to discern?<br />
Perhaps you’re a ghost, a vision, a hallucination buried in my psyche,<br />
But deep-down something whispers, that I have no right to apprehend you<br />
Be quick, the cameras absolutely monitor everything<br />
I’ll wipe the data I can, but I’m lost as to each iota that they scan.”</p>

<p>“Maybe they have my neck for it, but who am I to judge?<br />
Like our state’s great hero, I now feel grounded in my conviction.”</p>

<p>“Thank you, dear friend” as he hands back my belongings,<br />
“But you keep that one, as a token of my appreciation,<br />
And protection from any wrath they try to strike upon you.”</p>

<p>“May the road rise up to meet you<br />
May the wind always be at your back<br />
May the sun shine warm upon your face<br />
And rain fall soft upon your fields<br />
And until we meet again, may God<br />
Hold you in the palm of His hand.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The traveler attempts to enter Connecticut]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 4: Cambridge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/28/chapter-4-cambridge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 4: Cambridge" /><published>2025-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/28/chapter-4-cambridge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/28/chapter-4-cambridge.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-4-cambridge">Chapter 4: Cambridge</h1>

<p>Red socks, green shirts, and yellow bears<br />
A city once built by titans who honed their craft<br />
Willams, Russell, Orr, and Bird; names once synonymous with greatness<br />
Gone, mere memories, relics of what was</p>

<p>Embarked along the Charles, I turn toward the skyline<br />
Wrapped in fear I am, to see a city quaking in pain<br />
Buildings destroyed, sirens abound, helicopters serving (or protecting)<br />
A downtown perpetually under attack</p>

<p>So I ask my guide, “what has become of those fabled streets?<br />
The recipients of a battering ram at that.<br />
War-torn that city looks, while on these shores we safely observe.”</p>

<p>“It will all soon click, trust me on this one.<br />
That city you see is now merely a testing ground to train saboteurs.<br />
Rioting, looting, gearing up for the day,<br />
They enact these similar travesties on a scale one thousand-fold.”</p>

<p>“You see, the commonwealth was in a bind<br />
The pulse of the city had gone deathly quiet.<br />
So a desperate legislature put out a lease on city blocks no longer needed.<br />
My dear Harvard stepped in, and then MIT<br />
To create a playground for students with minds stuck in infancy.”</p>

<p>“The problems got worse, and the universities kept lending out money<br />
Gobbling up street after street until they owned the whole downtown.<br />
Every business has left the grid, and a once proud and bustling environment<br />
Has turned into a tomb.”</p>

<p>“Now on your left as far as your eye can see<br />
These are the perpetrators hiding behind their barricades.<br />
A fortress fomented in avarice, with absolutely no time for scruples.”</p>

<p>I look to my left, aghast,<br />
Full blocks of buildings ransacked,<br />
Stripped of their New England stateliness, hastily replaced,<br />
By iron and steel, drones all on the survey</p>

<p>A once proud neighborhood turned into a bunker</p>

<p>“I see nothing but Isengard, if you get that reference,<br />
How is it possible to see these institutions<br />
Fall into madness?”</p>

<p>My guide takes a second to wipe a tear from his cheek,<br />
“it’s the vicious cycle of the beast,<br />
It could not be tamed and grew unwieldy.<br />
With the advent of access to intelligence, the universities got desperate<br />
Unable to view themselves as anything other than early man’s voice of reason<br />
Arrogant enough to think bright minds had their own agency<br />
They doubled down on draconian doctrine and continued to push radical discourse.”</p>

<p>“Now Cambridge is all that remains in this once respectable city,<br />
The University system completely in shambles<br />
The highest bidders get in,<br />
The pricing algorithm oh-so fined tuned,<br />
Perfected financial engineering to justify their existence.”</p>

<p>“Sadly, there’s plenty across the world far and wide<br />
With cash to burn, and a moral compass off kilter<br />
To let their children be babysat inside this cold chrome chamber.”</p>

<p>Unable to contain himself, my guide weeps on a nearby bench.<br />
I put my arm around him, hoping to offer some solace.<br />
“I know your duty ties you to your city, but you must have heard<br />
Of success stories across other places in the union<br />
With new tech enabling swaths of people to discover their latent agency?”</p>

<p>“You know as well as I, the strength to do good is always inside.<br />
The University had its run to connect those in likeness of mind.<br />
But every dog has its day, and with new technology abound<br />
Deep down everyone knew its slow death had already begun.<br />
Even in my time, these murmurings were already happening,</p>

<p>“I’m sorry what happened to your Harvard, but if there’s a flicker of hope,<br />
This fortress is a last bastion of a dying dialect, an icon, a monument.<br />
I feel it, hope can still spring eternal, tell me Dear Harrison, am I right or am I wrong.”</p>

<p>He gathers himself and corroborates my notion, “but don’t forget,<br />
Wherever there’s success a force exists out to destroy.<br />
Newtonian mindset desperate to make life a zero-sum game.”</p>

<p>And like a jolt to my system, with an IV full of caffeine, I proclaim<br />
“Find it I shall, even if I must scour all our great topography!”</p>

<p>He smiles, “that the spirit my boy, but please do remember<br />
My statesmen true in their fortitude, and the negotiation I misplayed,<br />
Dying on my own sword.”</p>

<p>Energized and optimistic we scurry west on the Charles<br />
To an abandoned lot that contained<br />
My one ticket out.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The traveler learns about the university structure in this future dystopia]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 3: Boston</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/27/chapter-3-boston.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 3: Boston" /><published>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/27/chapter-3-boston</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/27/chapter-3-boston.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-3-boston">Chapter 3: Boston</h1>

<p>My swift-footed rescuer urged me to the front of the train<br />
Just as a gang of miscreants burst through<br />
Blood lusted for no particular reason<br />
Bellowing remarks about the anger of the day<br />
Unprovoked carnage for those on the wrong side of history</p>

<p>Yet this man, whoever he is<br />
Calmy helped me evade through an emergency door up front<br />
Dashing up a flight of stairs<br />
To witness my first daylight in what felt like months</p>

<p>His garb was peculiar<br />
Neatly put together in jacket and tie<br />
Hand-stitched?<br />
Oh, you better believe it!</p>

<p>Carrying the vibe of an aristocrat,<br />
He gave a deep bow before he spoke<br />
His words coming from a bygone era<br />
“Not often, my son, do men escape from that army of harpies.<br />
Driven by ideology fomented in this city’s barricades<br />
They lash out, and destroy as it is written in their syllabi.”</p>

<p>“But by that look in your eye, confusion even fear I can see<br />
I immediately know for certain, you are not one of them.<br />
Tell me then stranger traveler, what has compelled you to make that perilous journey<br />
From north to south?”</p>

<p>Visibly shaken, I respond with a stutter<br />
“I couldn’t possibly tell you<br />
My bearings are still so disoriented.<br />
What’s real or fake, alive or dead,<br />
Is it even in my destiny for me to find out?<br />
But what I do know, there’s an immovable force deep inside me<br />
Who claims to know my whereabouts”</p>

<p>He smiles with reassurance<br />
“You are not the first one I have met.<br />
Lost souls seeking answers here on God’s cosmic plain.<br />
Fitting you start in Boston, our nation’s first great city.”</p>

<p>“Here I stand before you with great dismay<br />
Walking these foreign streets night and day.<br />
Mayor I once was, I made a deal to politically survive<br />
And now, vanquished and banished,<br />
Lamenting what my great Massachusetts has become.”</p>

<p>“Hundreds of years ago there was turmoil abound<br />
Not so dissimilar to what is before us here and now.<br />
I assembled New England’s finest, in Hartford one winter<br />
To determine our states’ fate and a new path of self-sufficiency”</p>

<p>“A pragmatist I ultimately was<br />
Perhaps I should have been more fierce<br />
And followed the notions of my brethren<br />
Who were far more hellbent”</p>

<p>“As I look to the North<br />
And now New Hampshire and Maine sealed their fate<br />
In hardship, but purpose,<br />
To build their own nation state.”</p>

<p>“And me, Boston and Massachusetts missed their chance,<br />
So I’m stuck living with self doubt on what I could’ve done differently.”</p>

<p>“Come with me, you’ll see what this city has become.<br />
A glorified papermill of meaningless diplomas<br />
With arbitrary seals of approval.”</p>

<p>Calmer now I felt in the hands of so astute a guide<br />
I followed with no apprehension to learn more of where we went wrong.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The traveler meets his first mysterious guess]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 2: The Train Ride</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/26/chapter-2-the-train-ride.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 2: The Train Ride" /><published>2025-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/26/chapter-2-the-train-ride</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/26/chapter-2-the-train-ride.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-2---the-train-ride">Chapter 2 - The Train Ride</h1>

<p>My mysterious guide was right</p>

<p>With no guards in sight<br />
I began my long desolate walk to the Merrimack<br />
The North’s Rio Grande, Two Civilizations divided<br />
By what, I still don’t know<br />
Or if I even want to find out</p>

<p>To my dismay, I may not even have a choice<br />
Upon seeing a fiery mountain shooting up plumes<br />
Of smoke, exhaust, and the worst types of fumes<br />
A pile of abandoned railcars, left undoubtedly as a tomb<br />
Warning posts all around, telling defiant ones,<br />
WE SHOOT ON SIGHT<br />
Mass graves for the unlucky ones – who simply wanted out</p>

<p>Not even knowing how to turn back, I continue on in a rush<br />
As a rickety railcar approaches, graffitied back to front<br />
Hissing like a snake, seducing me to step on in</p>

<p>Captained by ghosts, how could this train be not?<br />
And me? Do I fit the bill of such a bone-chilling prophecy?<br />
I drum up the courage and enter the car furthest in the back</p>

<p>Newspapered windows, flickering lights, painted messages in languages illegible<br />
I sit and try to gauge the editorials and what they may elucidate<br />
The years are random 2030, 2040, all the way up to the late 2090s<br />
No real news so to speak – opinion pieces catering to the niches<br />
Not a surprise, journalism has always been a casualty to one click hysteria</p>

<p>Though one pieces catches my eye by a New Yorker named Lacroix<br />
Shouting absurdities about spacetime wrinkles<br />
Published in 2073<br />
Suggesting there are those walking among us with answers from different times</p>

<p>I clutch at a sharp pain in my chest<br />
Reading his words<br />
Memories flooding back with a gigantic gap in between,<br />
This present and my present, do I really know where I stand?<br />
Atoning for some misdeed, required answers, or just a hallucination?</p>

<p>My conscious mind won’t let me think this is anything but a dream<br />
Is this railcar, now picking up steam,<br />
a wicked trick from deep in my psyche?<br />
Who am I to say, as I begin to feel a longing<br />
For wife, kids, and family lost at some other point in time</p>

<p>And then, a voice cautiously whispers deep in my right ear<br />
Soothing me in an accent I know but never hear<br />
“Please put your faith in me,<br />
Far too long rationality has dominated your thought<br />
Eschewing eons of years of progress to render Yourself down<br />
To only what you can see”</p>

<p>“Fraught with destruction the course you’re on,<br />
Only by losing yourself will you ultimately be found<br />
The chaos engulfing you is immaterial<br />
Its not part of your synchronicity<br />
Deep down you know what to do,<br />
For once, I beg, trust your iron will and instinct”</p>

<p>And like a punch to my heart and soul<br />
It revives me for this heavy weight bout<br />
Ready to step into the ether<br />
And whatever it may hold</p>

<p>Alas, there’s no rest for the weary<br />
As I’m suddenly woken by screams, whistles, and chants<br />
Inside a station, I hadn’t realized we’d pulled in</p>

<p>Like a rapture banging on the door, it’d have shaken Peter to his core<br />
Declarations to take no prisoners by the assailants at large<br />
Yet here I am, the only one!</p>

<p>And like an olive branch extended from the front of the car<br />
A cloaked figure grabs me by my sweaty hand, shouting<br />
“Quickly. Follow me”</p>

<hr />

<p><em>End of Chapter 2</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The traveler takes a mysterious train from the New Hampshire border down to Boston]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 1: The Arrival</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/25/chapter-1-the-arrival.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 1: The Arrival" /><published>2025-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/25/chapter-1-the-arrival</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/25/chapter-1-the-arrival.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-1-the-arrival">Chapter 1: The Arrival</h1>

<p>Decades passed<br />
As far as I could tell<br />
My head pounding from a journey<br />
That I hadn’t asked for</p>

<p>To the base of a mountain,<br />
Capped with dirty wet snow<br />
Teeming with moose, wolves, and beasts of all kind</p>

<p>They’re not scared, I wonder why?<br />
I pull up my jacket, hoping for any kind of ride</p>

<p>Disheveled roads, no upkeep,<br />
DOT budgets are probably tight<br />
Until I arrive at a signpost<br />
Route 16; with a silhouette in the mountain</p>

<p>“Live Free or Die,”</p>

<p>It looks like some populace made its choice<br />
As a car approached from behind<br />
Camouflaged, dark, certainly unwelcome to any visitors</p>

<p>Suddenly, with a muzzle in my gut, he yells,<br />
“State your business now!”<br />
“I’m just a mere traveler, unaware<br />
Of the time, the date, or even the year</p>

<p>“Liar!”<br />
He’s careful not to cause a stir in wood<br />
“Embarking on these lands unwarranted<br />
Could be, for you, extremely costly”</p>

<p>He ruffles through my billfold<br />
Each card expired, expired, expired<br />
“What kind of cheap forgeries are these?<br />
You do realize these companies cease to exist?”</p>

<p>“Sir I beg you, where I am I do not know<br />
Pinch me, kick me, smack me<br />
Anything to wake me from this dream,<br />
This nightmare”</p>

<p>Suddenly convinced, he begins to change his tune<br />
“I see it now, you’re one of those,<br />
Your clothes and your belongings,<br />
Are all from a far-gone era”</p>

<p>“An era you may be wont to know<br />
delivered our continent into hysteria</p>

<p>Come, get in, you have no business here<br />
Your journey lies south<br />
In the continental land<br />
From which we in New Hampshire seceded”</p>

<p>“Ghost stories some call them<br />
But too frequent for that<br />
Talk of pilgrims like you<br />
Haunting us in the moonlight”</p>

<p>“You’re the first I have met, I trust your business is your own<br />
I’ll take you to the rail that leads to Boston<br />
As you begin to weave a narrative<br />
On the events that have caused this current state”</p>

<p>“Be cautious, yet hasty, use your gut on who to trust<br />
But be open to the lost souls<br />
Their stories paint our landscape”</p>

<p>“I leave you here<br />
The coast calls me for international supplies<br />
Mind the barbed wire at the border<br />
And the guards will cause you no harm<br />
Godspeed, he declares<br />
I hope you find what you need<br />
Often these journeys are internal<br />
So from me to you, let your mind and spirit be freed”</p>

<hr />

<p><em>End of Chapter 1</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A traveler awakens in a fractured America, encountering the seceded state of New Hampshire]]></summary></entry></feed>