<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-31T23:16:25-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">american-epic</title><subtitle>Repository for Poem Chapters</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Chapter 6: Connecticut Border</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/10/30/chapter-6-connecticut-border.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 6: Connecticut Border" /><published>2025-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/10/30/chapter-6-connecticut-border</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/10/30/chapter-6-connecticut-border.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-6-connecticut-border">Chapter 6: Connecticut Border</h1>

<p>We rush along to the lot, more of a junkyard if we’re lacking tact<br />
With cars, robots, drones, cranes and all types of machinery disassembled<br />
The clock blares again, and over a loudspeaker we hear<br />
A shrill voice leading a mantra with demonic undertones<br />
“Chosen ones, find it in your heart to stamp out hate at any cost<br />
Your life, their life, one in the same, is proper blood spilled<br />
Those fallen before you, were culled as they should be.”<br />
I shiver, appalled by what I’ve heard<br />
The care for human life on par with that of a gulag<br />
“That’s your cue my boy to get out of this state.<br />
By nightfall the streets teem with infernal practicing<br />
Of extracurriculars in hopes of finding in-flesh hosts and moments of reckoning.”</p>

<p>Like leaving a long lost family member<br />
My farewell cuts deeper than I expected<br />
“Thanks aren’t enough<br />
As you saved me from certain torment—<br />
Flying solo, I’d have met my maker”<br />
I help him hoist a tarp revealing five obscure vehicles<br />
He winks, “just because I look Victorian—<br />
Does not mean I have not learned to get my hands dirty.”</p>

<p>“Be swift, and take 90 to the west<br />
Your road gets brighter, I’m sure, when you hit Connecticut<br />
For me I’m back to the haunted train where we first met<br />
As something tells me there’s more like you to come<br />
To witness the chaos of this century”</p>

<p>I choose the most obscure car on the lot<br />
But still I cannot go—<br />
No pedal, brake, nor steering wheel.<br />
My guide just grins—<br />
Tossing me the keys, and pressing the ignition<br />
A robotic voice hums—<br />
“Destination please?”<br />
Not sure where to go, I blurt out the first place in my mind,<br />
“Krispy Pizza, Brooklyn, New York City”<br />
The machine pauses. Waiting…<br />
“No current match found—<br />
Redirecting to coordinates last archived in 2055”</p>

<p>Before I can ask if New York met a similar demise<br />
The car whirs away<br />
And him again<br />
Just a silhouette in my mirror<br />
Avoiding pothole madness in a reverse game of whack-a-mole<br />
MassDOT obviously disappeared with the tightening of the purse<br />
But who could blame them—<br />
If everyone left<br />
Leaving this thoroughfare so hauntingly empty</p>

<p>Eventually 90 became 84 and I head southwest<br />
To a state border crossing, the first of the journey—<br />
This one, purposefully ominous<br />
Miles of abandoned vehicles and trailers, glowing with neon lights<br />
Gargoyles perched on road-signs<br />
Grotesque tongues as long as their limbs<br />
A fair warning to those not welcome—<br />
“You’d best turn around.”</p>

<p>Still I press along confident in my intent<br />
Unencumbered by regulations existing in this new world<br />
When suddenly—<br />
My vehicles comes to a standstill<br />
Not even a screech from the brakes<br />
The whiplash from the seatbelt—<br />
A reminder I’m not at my own behest</p>

<p>A border patrolman comes out, inching closer, a rifle abreast<br />
Surveying me and my vehicle—<br />
Whether I’m any type of threat<br />
A bright light flashes from his pocket<br />
Too soon for me to shield my eyes<br />
And he yells with assertion, “State your destination.”<br />
My hands clam up, my brow lined with sweat<br />
“Oh dear god, what do I say?<br />
It’s true<br />
I’m just passing through<br />
But is that information sufficient?”<br />
“New York City sir, to visit a cousin for a reunion”<br />
Hoping my intuition works to keep my matters short and sweet.<br />
The guard’s face grows stern as he approaches nearer<br />
Followed by a beep from his device—<br />
Like a machine whirring on in error<br />
“You’re not in the national database<br />
Now cut out the lies.<br />
And if you don’t, I’m trained to assume—<br />
You’re a Northern spy<br />
With your crime being treason”</p>

<p>Solemn and pale I have no comeback to offer<br />
I feebly hand him my wallet as he starts shuffling through it<br />
His anger turned to confusion as he started uncovering its contents<br />
White knuckling an expired stack of credit cards<br />
“What is the point of counterfeiting artifacts so obtuse?”<br />
Until the final card he unveils immediately uplifts his tune<br />
A card— I sometimes forget—<br />
That has been in my possession for years<br />
It reveals an ode to a land of steep cliffs<br />
Enveloped in fog<br />
With a blessing of hope<br />
In deep times of need</p>

<p>In sudden revelation his world view turns on its axis<br />
His scowl morphs into a shape far less obscene<br />
He steps back, his rifle withdrawn<br />
A moment of longing etched on his face<br />
He closes his eyes<br />
Muttering something in deep contemplation<br />
“Its so rare these days to see relics of faith in these northern parts<br />
And coupled with these plastic relics,<br />
Who am I to discern?<br />
Perhaps you’re a ghost, a vision, a hallucination, or just a fraud with a printer<br />
But deep-down something whispers, that I have no right to apprehend you<br />
Be quick, the cameras absolutely monitor everything<br />
I’ll wipe the data I can, but I’m lost as to each iota that they scan.”<br />
“Maybe they have my neck for it, but who am I to judge?<br />
Like our state’s great hero, I now feel grounded in my conviction.”<br />
“Thank you” I sigh<br />
Lost for words after his benevolence<br />
“But you keep that one for safety as a token of my appreciation”</p>

<p>Just like that, I crawl through the archway<br />
Careful about my speed<br />
Praying for gladder tidings ahead<br />
And a more welcoming landscape<br />
“May the road rise up to meet you<br />
May the wind always be at your back<br />
May the sun shine warm upon your face<br />
And rain fall soft upon your fields<br />
And until we meet again, may God<br />
Hold you in the palm of His hand.”</p>

<hr />

<p><em>End of Chapter 6</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The traveler leaves Massachusetts and crosses into Connecticut]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 5: Cambridge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/30/chapter-5-cambridge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 5: Cambridge" /><published>2025-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/30/chapter-5-cambridge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/30/chapter-5-cambridge.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-5-cambridge">Chapter 5: Cambridge</h1>

<p>We march on towards Revere’s house<br />
Twisting and turning between the grey streets and debris<br />
Masterfully evading caws and chants from the North End procession</p>

<p>And his house, what a sight to behold!<br />
The dwelling of America’s first hero<br />
Unscathed and untouched by the chaos surrounding it all</p>

<p>So I ask<br />
“How’s it in pristine condition?<br />
Even the tombstones are untouched.<br />
It feels impossible, given everything else I’ve seen.”</p>

<p>“An astute observation – you’ll know soon enough<br />
Fortunately, some semblance of intelligent good<br />
Still has regard for the sacred.”</p>

<p>My guide looks over his shoulder<br />
As we inch nearer the entry<br />
The crowd still loud, but comfortably out of sight<br />
He neatly picks the lock, the man’s done this before<br />
He swings the door open, ushering me<br />
Into the pitch black greeting us in the catacomb</p>

<p>My guide moves gracefully<br />
As if led by some cosmic sonar<br />
He opens a trap door that emits neon green light<br />
He beckons me on, punching through my stiff apprehension<br />
I follow – guided by his certainty<br />
Once again down into the pits</p>

<p>“Put these on” he commands<br />
Throwing a wardrobe of revolutionary attire my way<br />
I buckle my shoes – the clicking I find quite satisfying<br />
The heavy wool itches, a scratch I cannot reach<br />
Yet oddly – I feel blanketed in its comfort</p>

<p>“This tunnel leads to the other side of the Charles<br />
And we’ll cross to a neighborhood<br />
Unrecognizable to any of your day<br />
Cambridge, my dear Cambridge and its orchestrated malevolence!<br />
Fomented by no oversight or regulation<br />
I press as to why–<br />
“What’s Cambridge’s role in all this?<br />
The Universities lost their pull in my time<br />
Grasping at any straw they could”</p>

<p>He paused to collect his thoughts<br />
Prepping his response<br />
“Everything, my dear boy<br />
Now let me tell you why”</p>

<p>“That downtown you saw is merely a testing ground<br />
To train saboteurs<br />
Rioting, looting, gearing up for the day<br />
They enact the same travesties on a scale hundredfold”</p>

<p>“You see, the commonwealth got desperate<br />
The pulse of a city and state dying under the weight of its debt<br />
And the Universities – yes you were correct – they were in a bind<br />
In their own dire state of affairs<br />
Desperate for students, anyone who’d pay the price<br />
But Harvard and MIT – being well endowed – rode the bumpy waters<br />
And didn’t stop there”</p>

<p>“They made a deal with the state<br />
Leasing city blocks to do what they pleased<br />
Scooping up street after street until each inch was theirs<br />
They curated a playground for students<br />
With their minds trapped in infancy<br />
A stunted doctrine – with personal development irrelevant”</p>

<p>He pauses a moment, massaging the cold tunnel wall<br />
Looking for something to pull<br />
He finds a latch and out springs a ladder<br />
Up he is instantly – and me<br />
Tuckered out in my wool costume, barely able to keep up</p>

<p>Off with a manhole cover<br />
The sun shining through enough to blind<br />
As it bounces off a brilliant metal<br />
Only such a material –<br />
Could rays catch and disarm us so</p>

<p>Now on Cambridge proper<br />
Perhaps I was better off staying beneath the streets<br />
Staring aghast at a mighty chrome structure<br />
A fortress – building no more – a laboratory<br />
Built out of anger</p>

<p>And the rubble that it displaced<br />
Each brilliant hall, hundreds of years old<br />
Not even a mere afterthought<br />
To a once decent society</p>

<p>My guide shakes his head<br />
“I avoid these shores as often as I can<br />
Seeing what they did to marvelous architecture<br />
It gets me every time.”</p>

<p>“In desperate moments is when the devil brings out his best tricks<br />
A teetering endowment, a crumbling state–<br />
The most dastardly of synergies”</p>

<p>“It was meant to be temporary<br />
But grew unwieldy<br />
Unlimited popularity to practice destruction with no consequence<br />
Could not be passed up by the bursar”</p>

<p>“So Harvard and MIT fused and grew as one<br />
The ideologues and the tech<br />
Admitting anyone willing to pay full price<br />
Blinded by their avarice<br />
Embracing their new roles–<br />
Provocateurs on the eastern shore</p>

<p>“Wait, wait, wait,” I interrupt<br />
“What’s the point? University to learn chaos?<br />
That’s all this boils down to?”</p>

<p>He takes a second, clarifying his thoughts</p>

<p>“Yes but lest you forget, brilliant minds are alive and well<br />
Misguided, certainly, but overcome the apprehension by a drive<br />
To test boundaries of what’s possible<br />
The one percenters get funneled into the usual suspects<br />
Big tech, banking, diplomacy, shady NGOs<br />
While the lemmings down in the streets are thrown into the bureaucrat grinder.”</p>

<p>“Its survival depends on its horrid mutation<br />
Even Faust would cringe<br />
Students groomed with no independent thought<br />
Or agency to stand alone on the mountain</p>

<p>We walk up to an iron barricade<br />
Fortified walls preventing us seeing the inside<br />
Bells ringing to usher a door open<br />
As a student procession files out</p>

<p>“Watch this,” my guide winks to me<br />
Confidently strutting towards a crew thirty strong</p>

<p>Not even ten meters near them does he make it<br />
Before a barrage of insults are thrown his way<br />
Much of the slander was gibberish to me<br />
Revolutionary apologists– how is that even a thing?<br />
Though I find it funny– fascist is still in vogue<br />
I guess some things never do change</p>

<p>Their jeers egg my guide on<br />
His soapbox growing higher by the second<br />
He breaks into soliloquy about Thomas Paine<br />
The hollering grows an octave higher<br />
After a minute of his comic dialogue<br />
He bows deep– wipes the spit from his brow<br />
Turning away from their sneers without a second look</p>

<p>“Ha, good fun, gotta stay entertained in some shape or form,<br />
Fortunately the code of conduct here states–<br />
No harm done north of the Charles in the light of day”</p>

<p>As an explosion deafens us<br />
South across the water from where we stand<br />
“Though the poor souls caught–<br />
In the wrong crosshairs over there<br />
Well, lucky for you that you found me”</p>

<p>Glad to be standing next to a new friend<br />
I sense our time is coming to an end<br />
As if he’s reading my mind he ushers me forward<br />
“Come there’s nothing left for you in Boston to see<br />
As much as I’d love to show you inside this new fortress<br />
You’d guess right that security is indeed tight<br />
Though all for naught the exercise would be<br />
Us being just ghosts outside of their databases”</p>

<p>“Keep on, I’ll get you south<br />
A whole country is left for you to explore<br />
One, I’ll add, not for the faint of heart<br />
But the pockets of goodness will make it<br />
Absolutely worth your while.”</p>

<p>“Just as Revere’s house stands tall<br />
It takes benevolence and a fighting spirit<br />
To deploy the right tech for the right reasons<br />
Holding onto a glimmer of hope<br />
For what this country once stood for.”</p>

<p>He hurried down the street<br />
Waving me along to follow<br />
Just as a bell tower struck five times<br />
Signalling a classic Northeast early autumn sundown</p>

<hr />

<p><em>End of Chapter 5</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The traveler explores Cambridge and prepares to leave Massachusetts]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 4: Boston</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/28/chapter-4-boston.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 4: Boston" /><published>2025-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/28/chapter-4-boston</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/28/chapter-4-boston.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-4-boston">Chapter 4: Boston</h1>

<p>Thunderous eruption slaps heavily from above<br />
I wake to chanting and cursing<br />
Banging on windows, pure savagery about<br />
A full array of colorful use of the tongue<br />
A mob without scruples<br />
No use in questioning<br />
Its intent to wreak havoc</p>

<p>The railcar is ironclad<br />
Quite the haven at the end of it all<br />
But surely the sanctuary fades away<br />
As soon as its black doors screech open</p>

<p>And a voice!<br />
“Up now! Come quickly!”</p>

<p>I shoot up, as if laying on hot coals<br />
To come face to face with the silhouette figure<br />
Who was no figment of my deep dream space</p>

<p>So peculiar, a man dressed in such antiquated garb<br />
At such an age<br />
Was able to maneuver with such grace<br />
He pushes open passenger doors<br />
Ushering me forward<br />
His speed had purpose, he had to have known<br />
What was on the other side of the barricade</p>

<p>The train creaks to a stop<br />
The doors crack open<br />
Yells bellow from the back of the train<br />
My guide pulls me out into blackness, out onto tarmac<br />
Safe for now, I hope<br />
From the madness we just escaped</p>

<p>“Through the hatch, come on up we go”<br />
How did he even see there was a ladder?<br />
Gripping each rung for dear life<br />
I follow in sheer obedience</p>

<p>With effortless ease, a manhole cover<br />
He hoists over his head<br />
We climb out onto the street above<br />
Dead center in what could only be described as a military drill</p>

<p>Sirens and blarehorns add to the fury<br />
Detonators fire off with brutal precision<br />
Smoke fills up all gaps<br />
Along with every nook and cranny previously left with clean air</p>

<p>“I know this place<br />
Many of times I walked these roads”<br />
I thought, pondering where I was</p>

<p>“Fanueil Hall, my boy”<br />
My guide says, with a pinch of despair<br />
Just as I was coming to my own recollection of happy youthful memories</p>

<p>A beautiful brick building it was<br />
But now, just art exhibit gone mad<br />
A spit in the face of our earliest forefathers<br />
The graffitied walls paying their sacrifices no mind</p>

<p>Robots, though, oddly enough<br />
Equipped to do nothing but scrub paint from the masonry<br />
Teemed the building, working with extreme precision</p>

<p>All for naught, so it would seem<br />
As tomorrow the same vulgarity would be right back on the brick</p>

<p>I turn back to my rescuer<br />
Deeply confused<br />
By him, this city, this entire exercise!<br />
He understands<br />
And we exchange a quick glance that is deeply and truly comforting</p>

<p>He gave a deep bow before he spoke again<br />
With the words and tone of a man from a bygone era:</p>

<p>“Not often my son do men escape the train from up north<br />
Good that I found you to avoid certain unpleasantries<br />
While dutybound I am to check the stations periodically<br />
It’s a stroke of luck, I was there at that precise point and time”</p>

<p>“I see your fear, your confusion<br />
You’re certainly not one of these modern men<br />
Tell me then, strange traveler<br />
What has compelled you to make the perilous journey<br />
From that forsaken Hampshire station?”</p>

<p>How to answer?<br />
So obvious a question it seemed<br />
Too obvious, in fact, every answer would be deemed imperfect</p>

<p>Still I try:<br />
“I’m figuring it out, poorly, I’m not gonna lie<br />
But I gotta tell you..<br />
Getting here was wild, dreamlike almost<br />
But this, it feels all so visceral<br />
It shocks me even more to see a black drape thrown over a once amazing city”<br />
He sighs briefly,<br />
“Your observation about my tormented home,<br />
It couldn’t cut deeper.<br />
I stand before you with great dismay<br />
Bound to walk these obscure streets night and day”</p>

<p>“Mayor I once was, way before your time<br />
I made a deal to survive politically<br />
Awry my bargain went<br />
Vanquished, then banished, and now–<br />
Brought back as penance to lament what my Massachusetts has become”</p>

<p>“Hundreds of years ago there was turmoil abound<br />
Our young nation was on the ropes<br />
Barely clinging for survival<br />
So I assembled New England’s finest - in Hartford one winter<br />
To determine our states’ fate, even a new path to self sufficiency”</p>

<p>“A pragmatist I ultimately was<br />
Perhaps I should have been more fierce in my youthful resolve<br />
And followed the notions of my brethren<br />
Who were far more hellbent”</p>

<p>“I look up to the North and see<br />
How New Hampshire and Maine sealed their fate<br />
In hardship,<br />
But purpose,<br />
In building their own nation state.”</p>

<p>Tears well in his eyes and I feel his pain<br />
Unaware, sadly, of how to provide any comfort<br />
So I nod with a genuine tone of acceptance<br />
Sharing a calm moment of silence</p>

<p>For a moment I can smell the salty ocean air<br />
A breeze to make Ishmael blush<br />
Hearkening me back to wine, good food, and chowder<br />
Oh chowder so hot, but so good, you don’t care that you burn your tongue</p>

<p>BANG<br />
BANG<br />
BANG!<br />
Bass drums - pounding erupts near the North End<br />
Chants are volleyed through the streets<br />
Growing louder as a procession approaches nearer</p>

<p>Shaken to his senses, my guide eyes me from head to toe:<br />
“No no, this will not do<br />
Look at your attire - you stick out like a sore thumb.<br />
That’s no pleasant chant you hear<br />
But a dutiful legion of my dear Harvard’s current crop of miscreants.”</p>

<p>“And my garb, ha!<br />
I fit in just fine, one perk of the sign of the times,<br />
I blend as an outlier might, when crazy is the day’s litmus test.<br />
Here, take my hat to start<br />
It gives you at least a bit of cover<br />
Until we get to Revere’s house and can fit you out properly.”</p>

<p>“From there we head to Cambridge<br />
A town once of crimson, now of iron and steel<br />
Back into the tunnels we go, best to avoid the lunatics training downtown<br />
You must witness the administrators that now own my University and city”</p>

<hr />

<p><em>End of Chapter 4</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The traveler learns about the Boston's demise and its position in shaping US dystopia]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 3: The Border Train</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/27/chapter-3-the-border-train.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 3: The Border Train" /><published>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/27/chapter-3-the-border-train</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/27/chapter-3-the-border-train.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-3-the-border-train">Chapter 3: The Border Train</h1>

<p>Its a dream<br />
It has to be<br />
There’s no other way<br />
This railcar cannot exist, I mean–<br />
Look at the years<br />
2060, 70, 80, 2090!<br />
The newspapered windows reveal<br />
Troubled stories through and through<br />
Surely for the most niche reader base</p>

<p>Yet one article<br />
Quickly catches my eye<br />
By a man named Krzyz<br />
Published in 2069</p>

<p>I skim the first paragraph<br />
Absurd wouldn’t begin to describe it<br />
Declaring how lost souls, including his own<br />
Can fall off the spacetime landscape</p>

<p>Tiny tremors pulse deep inside my chest<br />
I scoff and dismiss the theoretical pseudo physics<br />
Though I am compelled—<br />
By a reason I cannot describe<br />
To take the clipping, and fold it into my jean pocket</p>

<p>The train crawls on<br />
Surely I could walk faster<br />
My idle body lost in the vast solitude<br />
Of my deepest fears and anxieties<br />
The dim lights barely help<br />
Initiating a bone chilling exhaustion<br />
And a rest overcoming me, one which—<br />
I’m terrified if I’ll even wake</p>

<p>I cannot resist further<br />
As I’m brought to luminal sleep<br />
When I’m suddenly shaken by a voice<br />
In an accent I know<br />
But never hear</p>

<p>“Hola mi amor<br />
You know me, though you don’t realize it<br />
I’ve been with you since the beginning<br />
The half that keeps you going relentlessly”</p>

<p>“It was me, planting your wild ideas, foolish ones too<br />
Camping on peaks not meant for travelers—<br />
La Cabarga, Izoard, Angliru—<br />
There I was for you”</p>

<p>“I’m your Athena, your Penelope, even your Calypso<br />
Barricaded deep by ego for so long<br />
Rendered to the ghost in our hardware<br />
Combing through the darkest layer of our shadow”</p>

<p>“I’ve broken through<br />
Your mind is primed to believe<br />
In lands beyond the present<br />
And the discoveries we’ll unveil together<br />
We cannot retreat<br />
Too deep into the fray we have come<br />
In fact, how could we, when there’s nowhere to turn back to?<br />
That’s why the Krzyz article compelled you so deeply—<br />
Twists and turns<br />
No start<br />
No finish<br />
Just a trail of crumbs to push us on”</p>

<p>What the hell is happening?<br />
Surely there’s evil tricks aboard on this train<br />
I—</p>

<p>“You’re thinking too much, mi amor<br />
You’ve always failed at that<br />
We’ll trudge through eternal mud<br />
With that narrow and rational attitude of yours<br />
The world’s greatest among us tap into the unknown<br />
And if they have the fortitude to swim in murky waters<br />
That is when the universe reveals its greatest gifts”</p>

<p>“I know you too well, ha!<br />
You’d never be able to do this alone<br />
So—<br />
Do you trust me, to place your faith strongly<br />
In something real for the first time in years?”</p>

<p>My chest tightens, her words pierce like a dagger to my gut<br />
She’s right, I know it—<br />
Years wasted giving into foolish pride<br />
Vulnerability smeared across my face<br />
But why now? —</p>

<p>“STOP again!<br />
Don’t think too much<br />
There’s never a right time to take the plunge<br />
If I need to spoonfeed it to you<br />
Fine, I guess that’s what it takes<br />
A baby step first, to stay on this train”</p>

<p>Yes, I can do that, I will do that<br />
I get it now—<br />
What feels like a lifetime ago<br />
When we threw caution to the wind<br />
Responsible only for ourselves<br />
Chance felt like a guarantee<br />
A winner’s swagger that has been lost</p>

<p>“I foresee it now your confidence growing<br />
With each passing day—<br />
Until we’re thinking in unison<br />
Our thoughts indecipherable from one another”</p>

<p>My body begins to warm<br />
A blanket nestled upon my thoughts<br />
As the sublime state<br />
Between conscious and dreams tugs me down—<br />
For a final deep sleep</p>

<p>As I close my eyes thinking of the journey ahead<br />
My mind plays one last trick<br />
Conjuring a silhouette at the front of the railcar</p>

<hr />

<p><em>End of Chapter 3</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The traveler experiences a mystical encounter aboard the train]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 2: The Train Ride</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/26/chapter-2-no-mans-land.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 2: The Train Ride" /><published>2025-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/26/chapter-2-no-mans-land</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/26/chapter-2-no-mans-land.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-2---the-train-ride">Chapter 2 - The Train Ride</h1>

<p>My mysterious guide was right</p>

<p>With no guards in sight<br />
I began my long desolate walk to the Merrimack<br />
The North’s Rio Grande, Two Civilizations divided<br />
By what, I still don’t know<br />
Or if I even want to find out</p>

<p>To my dismay, I may not even have a choice<br />
Upon seeing a fiery mountain shooting up plumes<br />
Of smoke, exhaust, and the worst types of fumes<br />
A pile of abandoned railcars, left undoubtedly as a tomb<br />
Warning posts all around, telling defiant ones,<br />
WE SHOOT ON SIGHT<br />
Mass graves for the unlucky ones – who simply wanted out</p>

<p>Not even knowing how to turn back, I continue on in a rush<br />
As a rickety railcar approaches, graffitied back to front<br />
Hissing like a snake, seducing me to step on in</p>

<p>Captained by ghosts, how could this train be not?<br />
And me? Do I fit the bill of such a bone-chilling prophecy?<br />
I drum up the courage and enter the car furthest in the back</p>

<p>Newspapered windows, flickering lights, painted messages in languages illegible<br />
I sit and try to gauge the editorials and what they may elucidate<br />
The years are random 2030, 2040, all the way up to the late 2090s<br />
No real news so to speak – opinion pieces catering to the niches<br />
Not a surprise, journalism has always been a casualty to one click hysteria</p>

<p>Though one pieces catches my eye by a New Yorker named Lacroix<br />
Shouting absurdities about spacetime wrinkles<br />
Published in 2073<br />
Suggesting there are those walking among us with answers from different times</p>

<p>I clutch at a sharp pain in my chest<br />
Reading his words<br />
Memories flooding back with a gigantic gap in between,<br />
This present and my present, do I really know where I stand?<br />
Atoning for some misdeed, required answers, or just a hallucination?</p>

<p>My conscious mind won’t let me think this is anything but a dream<br />
Is this railcar, now picking up steam,<br />
a wicked trick from deep in my psyche?<br />
Who am I to say, as I begin to feel a longing<br />
For wife, kids, and family lost at some other point in time</p>

<p>And then, a voice cautiously whispers deep in my right ear<br />
Soothing me in an accent I know but never hear<br />
“Please put your faith in me,<br />
Far too long rationality has dominated your thought<br />
Eschewing eons of years of progress to render Yourself down<br />
To only what you can see”</p>

<p>“Fraught with destruction the course you’re on,<br />
Only by losing yourself will you ultimately be found<br />
The chaos engulfing you is immaterial<br />
Its not part of your synchronicity<br />
Deep down you know what to do,<br />
For once, I beg, trust your iron will and instinct”</p>

<p>And like a punch to my heart and soul<br />
It revives me for this heavy weight bout<br />
Ready to step into the ether<br />
And whatever it may hold</p>

<p>Alas, there’s no rest for the weary<br />
As I’m suddenly woken by screams, whistles, and chants<br />
Inside a station, I hadn’t realized we’d pulled in</p>

<p>Like a rapture banging on the door, it’d have shaken Peter to his core<br />
Declarations to take no prisoners by the assailants at large<br />
Yet here I am, the only one!</p>

<p>And like an olive branch extended from the front of the car<br />
A cloaked figure grabs me by my sweaty hand, shouting<br />
“Quickly. Follow me”</p>

<hr />

<p><em>End of Chapter 2</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The traveler takes a mysterious train from the New Hampshire border down to Boston]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 1: The Arrival</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/25/chapter-1-the-arrival.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 1: The Arrival" /><published>2025-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/25/chapter-1-the-arrival</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chapters/2025/09/25/chapter-1-the-arrival.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="chapter-1-the-arrival">Chapter 1: The Arrival</h1>

<p>Decades passed<br />
As far as I could tell<br />
Head pounding<br />
Heart racing<br />
Feet stuck to the ground</p>

<p>At the base of a mountain,<br />
Capped with dirty wet snow<br />
Teeming with moose, wolves, and beasts of all kind<br />
They observe, unbothered by my presence</p>

<p>The lone road ground down to the bone<br />
Offset by the intricate barbed wire<br />
Guiding the full stretch of the shoulder</p>

<p>Dread creeps in of my unwanted presence<br />
Rifling blood down to my legs, as I wander away<br />
I arrive at a signpost<br />
Barely visible with the gray moon waning<br />
Route 16; a silhouette in the mountain<br />
“Live Free or Die,”<br />
It looks like some had made their choice</p>

<p>I continue on with a glimmer of hope<br />
To come in contact with someone who can provide any clarity<br />
Though as soon as my thought finishes, I rue what I had spoken<br />
To hear a caravan of vehicles slowly approaching</p>

<p>The nearest thicket provides enough cover<br />
To hear but not be seen<br />
And the fortune of knowing my deep breaths<br />
Could not be heard over their motors blaring</p>

<p>Dozens of jeeps, trailers, tanks, and bikes<br />
Even three contraptions hovering above the ground!<br />
The vehicles are painted fresh<br />
Dark blue and gold<br />
Peppered with slogans and chants<br />
Even a few in French</p>

<p>Slowly they move, like a funeral march<br />
Distancing themselves from torment<br />
Into the safety of their white capped peaks</p>

<p>I creep out, careful to stay close to the shoulder<br />
In case a rogue vehicle has a reason to turn back<br />
Transfixed by what’s behind,<br />
Indifferent to what’s in front<br />
A stealth vehicle intercepts me,<br />
In its crosshairs,<br />
I’m a sitting duck at its disposal</p>

<p>A man bursts out of this Lantern Rouge<br />
Camouflaged, coon-skin cap<br />
Like a trapper marching towards the Hudson</p>

<p>His machine gun drawn at the ready<br />
He shouts in a thick Quebecois tone<br />
“You there!<br />
What are you doing?<br />
All citizens should know,<br />
Trespassing the white mountain is punishment by death!”</p>

<p>The ice on the pines wasn’t as cold as my blood<br />
Frozen to the spot I could barely exclaim<br />
“D’d’don’t shoot, don’t shoot!”<br />
I throw my hands in the air<br />
Praying to give off the effect<br />
A moment of true and honest surrender</p>

<p>Gun still raised<br />
Unperturbed<br />
Not blinking<br />
Sucking out all the power I had left in me</p>

<p>“Billfold” he shouts “Documents now”<br />
Somehow I had my wallet, a minor miracle I suppose<br />
He ruffles through it, slower with each card he finds<br />
Aghast at what the headlights reveal in the dates</p>

<p>“Expire, expire, expire, tous les sont expires”<br />
He curses in French<br />
“Where have you found these cheap knock off forgeries?”</p>

<p>And finally, perhaps by divine grace<br />
He pulls out a photo, me and a smiling family of four<br />
A sunkissed backdrop, a perfect golden hour<br />
Emitting enough light and radiance<br />
To cut through our pale encounter</p>

<p>Tears in his eyes, he suddenly realized<br />
“C’est vrai, cest vrai<br />
Everything my friends said<br />
I thought they were drunk, or how you say<br />
Defonce”</p>

<p>“They too found lurkers in the forest<br />
Abandoned by time.<br />
Mon Dieu! And you! Oui, haha!<br />
This whole time they were right!”</p>

<p>“You see, I cry for your family,<br />
I have one too<br />
I see them, maybe once per year<br />
A lonely life of a soldier.”</p>

<p>“But to you, this is nonsense, non”<br />
You can’t begin to comprehend<br />
The dates on your cards are still too old<br />
To realize we’re at the bottom.”</p>

<p>He lights a cigarette<br />
Takes a few puffs and breathes<br />
“You see, my duty is on patrol,<br />
Boring<br />
So I have plenty of time to think.”</p>

<p>“They say you can destroy anything worth building<br />
In a moment or an instant<br />
But true evil,<br />
Cunning evil,<br />
How you say, waits, non<br />
Bides its time<br />
It festers, it rots<br />
And then one day, everything is sulfur<br />
The smell cannot come out.”</p>

<p>“Until you cut off the hand of the beast<br />
That’s what we did.<br />
We left - we govern ourselves<br />
We’re figuring it out<br />
So it goes allying with the Northern States”<br />
“Life isn’t kind to us.<br />
That’s okay<br />
But we’re free and independent<br />
To do as we please.”</p>

<p>“And your family, wherever they are<br />
How you get back to them<br />
I think….<br />
Is only by going south.”</p>

<p>“See what your country has become”</p>

<p>“I’ll take you to the border<br />
Please be on garde<br />
We’re cut off from the states<br />
News is hazy, I have no intel<br />
With what to warn you.”</p>

<p>“One point for me,<br />
A pint to my name<br />
If you’re kind enough to give me a credit card<br />
So my mates know I’m not insane.”</p>

<p>I oblige knowing these cards are useless here<br />
Such a small token for benevolence amid this fear<br />
I thank him as he dumps me off<br />
On a vast open plane<br />
In American New England<br />
Our expansive wasteland</p>

<hr />

<p><em>End of Chapter 1</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chapters" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A traveler awakens in a fractured America, encountering the seceded state of New Hampshire]]></summary></entry></feed>